Andrew Haven drew.haven@stanford.edu 650.967.1827

March 6, 2010

Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. Palo Alto, CA

To whom it may concern:

I love to program. It is where I am most comfortable and at home. Over the last four years of working and studying for a Masters in CS at Stanford, the most fun I have had programming was during the compilers course. Compilers are one of the most complex and elegant pieces of software I've encountered. The degree of complexity, abstractness, and correctness that are required is invigorating. When I saw a posting for a compiler engineer dealing with OpenCL I had to apply, as another passion of mine is distributed, concurrent, and GPU computation.

I am passionate about programming, and to that end I am constantly seeking to improve at my craft and try new things. I have dabbled in over a dozen languages over the years, and I frequently try new tools and techniques to improve my productivity. My current job has me working largely alone. I want to work with a team, integrating and collaborating with teammates to create larger and grander systems than I can achieve alone.

My vocational background is largely in systems administration and web programming, but that is only because it was the most active area of hiring when I entered the workforce with a degree in Physics, and at the time my focus was on network security. I have been programming since I was 10 and have never lost the love of burying myself in an afternoon of debugging. In order to improve my programming background I am currently working towards a Masters in CS at Stanford part-time through SCPD, and I intend to continue until I graduate. Working while I study allows me to immediately and directly apply the things I learn, and gives me a context for everything I hear in the classroom.

I look forward to working with one of the major companies in the processor market, and to be on the forefront of technology tackling this new world of multi-core and multi-system computing. I hope to hear from you soon as I am eager to start a chapter in my career.

Sincerely,

Andrew Haven

Andrew Haven

drew.hav en@gmail.com // 650-967-1827

EXPERIENCE

2006-present	Computer Analyst Stanford University
	 Wrote software for experiments used in published research using Matlab and C.
	\bullet Acted as the sole IT contact and administrator for the department, consisting of ${\sim}50$ users and many heterogeneous systems.
	 Administered private network of about 30 systems with centralized logins, networked file systems, and centralized licencing.
	Setup, maintained, and monitored file and web servers for each lab.Designed and implemented a multi-tier backup system.
	 Implemented automatic backups for desktops. Designed and developed MVC web applications using for time tracking, scheduling, and presentation evaluation.
2006	Web Developer Infospider
	 Developed CRM, CMS and flat websites for clients. Assisted designers with SEO.
2005-2006	Freelance Web Developer
	 Worked directly with clients to determine project scope and specifications.
	\bullet Designed and developed two e-commerce web sites for small businesses.
2005	Contract Cable Monkey Streamline Communications
	 Assisted with the setup and tear down of network infrastructure surrounding events at the San Jose Convention Center.
	 Provided help desk support to customers at the convention center.
EDUCATION	
2008-present	M.S. Computer Science (in progress) Stanford University through SCPD
	Focus on software theory
2001-2005	B.S. Applied Physics University of California, Santa Cruz
	Focus on computational physics Minor in mathematics Thesis on genetic algorithms for high dimensional optimization problems
SKILLS	
Dev elopment	C, C++, Haskell, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Javascript, SVN, Git
Web	Apache, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, Mongrel, HTML, CSS
Systems Administration	Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Solaris Services: NIS, NFS, ZFS, Samba, CIFS, SMB, SSH, DNS, NAT, TCP/IP